Adam H. Trotta

 Poston, MA
 ■ ahtrotta@gmail.com
 ★ adamtrotta.com
 in LinkedIn
 C) GitHub

PROFILE

I am a software engineer that loves solving problems with code! I recently built Bastion, a scalable and customizable backend system deployed with AWS using Docker containers. Previously, I conducted research in organic chemistry, leading to several peer-reviewed publications and a book chapter.

EXPERIENCE

Co-Creator, Software Engineer, Bastion

2022

- ullet Designed and created Bastion (bastion-baas.github.io oxdot), a scalable, open-source Backend-as-a-Service that is deployed to the cloud with AWS
- Collaborated with a fully remote team using GitHub and Notion to develop Bastion
- Containerized and deployed backend applications built with Express and MongoDB that provide database operations, user authentication, and file storage
- Implemented custom Cloud Code functions with AWS Lambda functions
- Enabled Bastion to support multiple backends by using AWS ECS for container orchestration
- Built an admin dashboard using React/Redux that manages backend deployment, custom Cloud Code functions, users, files, and database collections
- Automated Bastion cloud deployment using AWS CloudFormation
- Developed Bastion SDK, a JavaScript library facilitating communication between Bastion and client frontend apps
- Authored the technical case study detailing Bastion's design and implementation

Full-Stack Web Developer

2020 - 2022

- RequestPool: A Node.js application built with Express, Mongo, and PostgreSQL to capture and monitor webhooks
- Mellow: A Node.js kanban board application built using Express, Mongo, and React/Redux
- Todos: A todo tracking app built with vanilla JavaScript on the frontend, and Node.js/Express for the backend

Postdoctoral Research Fellow, Harvard University

2018 - 2020

- Discovered methods for precisely synthesizing complex carbohydrates
- Mentored graduate students in organic chemistry research
- Wrote and edited research articles and grant applications

SKILLS

Languages

JavaScript, Ruby, Go, SQL, HTML, CSS, Bash

Libraries & Frameworks

Express, Mongoose, React, Redux, Jest, ¡Query

AWS Cloud Technologies

CloudFormation, ECS Fargate, Lambda, S3, ALB, Cloud Map, EFS, IAM

Technologies

Git, GitHub, Docker, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Linux, REST APIs

EDUCATION

Software Development, *Launch School* ♂

2020 - 2022

Multi-year full-stack software engineering curriculum using mastery-based learning

Ph.D. Organic Chemistry, Weill Cornell Graduate School

2013 - 2018

Developed an efficient synthetic strategy for antibacterial compounds

M.A. Organic Chemistry, Columbia University

2012 - 2013

Conducted research in natural product total synthesis | GPA: 4.00

B.S. Chemistry, Tufts University

2008 - 2012

Completed a Senior Honors Thesis on carbohydrate synthesis | GPA: 3.80 | Summa Cum Laude